i'm gonna teach you how to animate stuff
in blender uh we're starting off with a
character do whatever you want man i
have a happy man
now you might want to consider
decimating your model every computer is
different though you just don't want to
start a fire shift aid add armature
we're going to add a single bone but
it's gone so we're going to
go into viewport display and make it in
front so that way we can forever see it
in front of the model g to grab
s to scale r to rotate in edit mode you
want to extrude more bones wherever bone
should go
you should put it there remember to
check different perspectives that way
the bones line up with the body because
remember it's a 3d object it's important
now that you have all your bones go back
into object mode
select your character first shift select
your bones second
your bone should be the lighter color
control p armature deform automatic
weights with your bone selected you
should be able to go into pose mode and
now you can move your character he's a
puppet so keyframes i like to select
this automatic keyframe it's just a dot
and as you move through the timeline you
can move the bones and the keyframes
will be made
and if you want a repeated action you
can copy and paste your selected frames
and make them
wave anything you create can now be your
puppet you are
god now